Guide to the J. Walter Thompson Company. San Francisco Office Records, 1949-1999 and undated RL.00746
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
J. Walter Thompson Company. San Francisco Office records
1949-1999 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
J. Walter Thompson Company. San Francisco Office
RL.00746
5.8 Linear Feet
Founded in 1864, the J. Walter Thompson Company (JWT) is one of the oldest and largest enduring advertising agencies in the United States. The JWT San Francisco office was opened in 1923. The JWT San Francisco Office Records span the years 1959-1999, and includes advertising proofs, commercial artwork, print schedules, marketing plans, manuals, company history materials, correspondence, Creative Library catalogs and audiovisual materials (audio cassettes, VHS video cassettes and videotapes). Also included are the papers of Harry A. Lee, a JWT executive involved in the development of JWT's Pacific Rim business during the 1960s. Companies represented in the collection include California Raisin Advisory Board, Dean Witter, Ferry-Morse Seed Company, Labatt's, Morris Plan, and Schlage. JWT offices touched on in the collection include New York, Manila (Philippines) and Tokyo (Japan). Acquired as part of the John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History.
1800 Items
Access Restrictions
Collection is restricted
Unpublished materials are closed to non-JWT researchers for fifteen years from the date of creation.
Original audiovisual materials are closed to use. Use of these materials may require production of listening or viewing copies. Please contact Research Services before coming to use this collection.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The J. Walter Thompson Company. San Francisco Office Records were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 1987 with additions in subsequent years.
Biographical Note
Harry A. Lee Biography
1910 Jan. 10 Born, Santa Monica, Calif.
1920s-1931 Educated at Principia High School, St. Louis, Missouri and Stanford University
1931 McCarty Advertising Agency, Los Angeles
1936 Media research, junior account representative, JWT San Francisco Office
1942-1945 Commissioned Lieutenant J.G. Commanded naval air patrols from Canal Zone, Central and South America. Later a navigator for Naval Air Transport Service, Pacific and Far East areas. Discharged after the war as a Lieutenant Commander
1945 Founded and operated Philippine Advertising Associates Inc., in Manila and Japan Advertising Associates in Tokyo
1955 Sold agencies to JWT and rejoined the agency as Vice President and Pacific Area Manager
1958-1963 Director of School Board, Hillsborough, Calif.
1961 Chairman, Advertising Committee, Invest in America
1960-1964 San Francisco Chamber of Commerce: Director and member of the Executive Committee (1960-1964); President (1962-1963); Chairman, Board of Directors (1964)
Collection Overview
The JWT San Francisco Office Records span the years 1959-1999, and includes advertising proofs, commercial artwork, print schedules, marketing plans, manuals, company history materials, correspondence, Creative Library catalogs and audiovisual materials (audio cassettes, VHS video cassettes and videotapes). Also included are the papers of Harry A. Lee, a JWT executive involved in the development of JWT's Pacific Rim business during the 1960s. Companies represented in the collection include California Raisin Advisory Board, Dean Witter, Ferry-Morse Seed Company, Labatt's, Morris Plan, and Schlage. JWT offices touched on in the collection include New York, Manila (Philippines) and Tokyo (Japan).
Collection Arrangement
The collection is organized into three series: Harry A. Lee Papers, General Office Files and Audiovisual Materials. The Harry A. Lee Papers include correspondence, clippings, and memoranda. General Office Files include primarily documents from the 1980s and 1990s including advertisements, a Creative Library and materials relating to JWT's 125th anniversary. Audiovisual Materials include videotapes and non-print media. Where possible, original folder titles have been retained.
Advertising agencies -- United States; Advertising agencies -- United States -- History; Advertising agencies -- Management; Advertising -- United States -- History; Advertising agencies -- History; J. Walter Thompson Company. Tokyo Office; Advertising -- History; J. Walter Thompson Company. New York Office; J. Walter Thompson Company. San Francisco Office; J. Walter Thompson Company -- History; J. Walter Thompson Company. Manila Office; Advertising agencies -- Philippines; J. Walter Thompson Company; Advertising executives; Advertising agencies -- Japan; Advertising executives -- United States; Proofs (printed matter); Audiocassettes; Videocassettes; Videotapes; Dean Witter & Co; Ferry-Morse Seed Company; J. Walter Thompson Company. San Francisco Office; John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History; Labatt's Canada Limited; Morris Plan Bankers Association
- General Office Files1987-1999 and undated, 3 boxes
  Scope and Contents note
  Includes reports, surveys, printed materials, samples of advertisements and logo designs, and catalogs of the Creative Library holdings. Organized alphabetically. Original folder titles were retained where possible.
  Conditions Governing Access note
  Restrictions on Access: Unpublished materials are closed to non-JWT researchers for 15 years from the date of creation.
  - Creative Library reports, 1994 Sept.-1996 Dec., 7 folders (Box 1)
  - Digital marketing reports, Hunter Madsen, 1996 (Box 1)
  - Earthquake, 1989 (Box 1)
  - Employee survey, 1992 (Box 1)
  - Hong Kong advertisements, 1998 (Box 1)
    [Includes International Fund for Animal Welfare and San Miguel beer.]
  - JWT 125th anniversary, 1988-1989, 1 of 4 folders (Box 1)
    [Includes Treasures of the World Mint Gulfstream commemorative coin information.]
  - JWT 125th anniversary, 1988-1989 (continued), 2-4 of 4 folders (Box 2)
  - Mounted logos, undated (Box 2)
    [Includes American Express, IBM, Kodak, Levi's, Porsche and Sony.]
  - Outdoor advertisements, 1994 (Box 2)
  - Print advertisements, 1998 (Box 2)
  - Print production reports, 1995 June-1996 Dec., 4 folders (Box 2)
  - Printed materials--JWT/SF of the 50s, Tom Yamada, 1998 (Box 2)
  - Thompson Night Handbook, 1987 (Box 2)
  - General Office Files--Restricted Materials, 1997-1999
    Subseries scope/content note.
    - Creative Library reports, 1997-1999, 6 folders (Box R1)
    - Print production reports, 1998-1999, 4 folders (Box R1)
    - Gulfstream commemorative coin (removed from JWT 125th anniversary materials) (Box R1)
- Harry A. Lee Papers, 1949-1966, 2 boxes
  Henry Lee was a JWT executive active in the development of JWT's Pacific Rim expansion. Includes correspondence, client files and materials relating to various JWT offices. Arranged alphabetically. Original folder titles have been maintained where possible.
  - Biographical sketch, 1961 (Box 3)
  - California Raisin Advisory Board, 1964-1965 (Box 3)
  - Cole & Weber, 1965 (Box 3)
  - Correspondence, 1964-1966, 7 folders (Box 3)
  - Dean Witter, 1964-1966, 3 folders (Box 3)
  - Ferry-Morris Seed Company, 1964-1965 (Box 3)
  - Ford, 1965 (Box 3)
  - Hillsborough (CA) school board, 1962 (Box 3)
  - Japan trip, 1964 (Box 3)
  - Labatt's, 1964 (Box 3)
  - Lowell Mainland, 1950-1957 (Box 3)
  - Memoranda, 1965 (Box 3)
  - Morris Plan Company, 1964 (Box 3)
  - National Conference of Christians and Jews annual dinner, 1965 (Box 3)
  - Offices of JWT
    - Chicago, 1964-1965 (Box 3)
    - Detroit, 1964-1965 (Box 3)
    - Los Angeles/Hollywood, 1964-1965 (Box 3)
    - Manila, 1964-1965 (Box 3)
    - New York, 1964-1965, 1 of 3 folders (Box 3)
    - New York, 1964-1965 (continued), 2-3 of 3 folders (Box 4)
    - Philippines, 1952-1954 and undated (Box 4)
    - San Francisco, 1964-1965 (Box 4)
    - San Francisco Office histories, 1953-1968 (Box 4)
    - Tokyo, 1964-1965 (Box 4)
  - San Francisco Chamber of Commerce, 1949-1966, 5 folders (Box 4)
  - Schlage Lock Company, 1964 (Box 4)
  - Southern Pacific Railroad, Western Pacific Control, 1960 (Box 4)
  - Stanley Resor/Jim Young materials, 1951-1956 (Box 4)
  - United Bay Area Crusade Christmas album, 1965 (Box 4)
- Audiovisual Materials, 1994-1997 and undated
  Arranged by format and alphabetically by title.
  Restrictions on Access: Unpublished materials are closed to non-JWT researchers for 15 years from the time of creation. Original audiovisual materials are closed to research until use copies can be produced.
  - Audiocassettes
    - Agency presentation reel. Undated. Audio cassette. TRT: 5:30 (Box AV1)
    - Agency reel. 1995. Audio cassette. TRT: 1:50 (Box AV1)
    - Agency reel. 1995. Audio cassette. TRT: 4:40 (Box AV1)
    - CA state lottery. 1996. Audio cassette. TRT: :60 (Box AV1)
    - California state lottery. Undated. Audio cassette. TRT: :60 (Box AV1)
    - California state lottery. 1995. Audio cassette. TRT: 2:00 (Box AV1)
    - California state lottery. 1995. Audio cassette. TRT: :60 (Box AV1)
    - Creative. 1994. Audio cassette. TRT: 5:00 (Box AV1)
    - Creative department. 1995. Audio cassette. TRT: :60 (Box AV1)
    - Creative library. 1995. Audio cassette. TRT: 8:45 (Box AV1)
    - Creative library. 1995. Audio cassette. TRT: 5:30 (Box AV1)
    - Creative library reel. 1996. Audio cassette. TRT: 5:00 (Box AV1)
    - Creative reel. 1997. Audio cassette. TRT: 3:00 (Box AV1)
    - Creative reel. 1997. Audio cassette. TRT: :60 (Box AV1)
    - Creative reel. 1997. Audio cassette. TRT: :60 (Box AV1)
    - JWT creative. 1995. Audio cassette. TRT: :60 (Box AV1)
    - JWT creative library. 1995. Audio cassette. TRT: 6:00 (Box AV1)
    - JWT Creative library. 1994. Audio cassette. TRT: 2:20 (Box AV1)
    - Lyon's restaurants. 1996. Audio cassette. TRT: 2:00 (Box AV1)
    - Nestle creative library. 1997. Audio cassette. TRT: :60 (Box AV1)
    - Sprint. 1997. Audio cassette. TRT: 1:52 (Box AV1)
  - Videocassettes
    - Agency presentation reel. 1995. VHS. TRT: 7:15 (Box AV1)
    - Agency reel. 1995. VHS. TRT: 9:00 (Box AV1)
    - Agency reel. 1995. VHS. TRT: 1:30 (Box AV1)
    - Agency reel. 1995. VHS. TRT: 1:30 (Box AV1)
    - California state lottery. 1995. VHS. TRT: 1:30 (Box AV1)
    - Creative department. 1995. VHS. TRT: 11:30 (Box AV1)
    - Creative reel. 1995. VHS. TRT: 4:00 (Box AV1)
    - Creative reel. 1994. VHS. TRT: 5:00 (Box AV1)
    - JWT creative. 1995. VHS. TRT: 3:00 (Box AV1)
    - JWT creative library. 1995. VHS. TRT: 5:00 (Box AV1)
    - JWT creative library. 1995. VHS. TRT: :30 (Box AV1)
    - JWT creative library. 1994. VHS. TRT: 3:00 (Box AV1)
    - Lyon's restaurants. 1995. VHS. TRT: :60 (Box AV1)
    - Nestle (Baby Ruth). Undated. VHS. TRT: :60 (Box AV1)
    - San Francisco highlight reel. Undated. VHS. TRT: 30:00 (Box AV1)
    - Sprint. 1995. VHS. TRT: 2:30 (Box AV1)
    - Sprint. 1995. VHS. TRT: 1:30 (Box AV1)
    - Sunsweet prunes. 1995. VHS. TRT: :60 (Box AV1)
  - Video tape
    - Agency presentation reel. 1995. 1-inch. TRT: 7:15 (Box AV2)
    - CA lottery/ chevron/ nestle. 1996. 1-inch. TRT: 7:30 (Box AV2)
    - Creative library. 1996. 1-inch. TRT: 1:30 (Box AV2)
    - Creative library reel. 1996. 1-inch. TRT: 3:15 (Box AV2)
    - Creative library reel sprint. 1996. 1-inch. TRT: 4:00 (Box AV2)
    - Creative library/March. 1997. 1-inch. TRT: 3:45 (Box AV2)
    - Creative reel. 1997. 1-inch. TRT: 1:30 (Box AV2)
    - Creative reel. 1997. 1-inch. TRT: :60 (Box AV2)
    - Creative reel. 1997. 1-inch. TRT: 1:30 (Box AV2)
    - Creative reel. 1996. 1-inch. TRT: 12:45 (Box AV2)
    - Creative reel 9 spots tied. 1996. 1-inch. TRT: 4:15 (Box AV2)
    - Nestle creative library (3 spots tied). 1997. 1-inch. TRT: 1:15 (Box AV2)
    - Sprint. 1997. 1-inch. TRT: 2:00 (Box AV2)